Phil: well, I think we've
confidentiality in general with
any sort of data protection for
any human being is important.
And the one thing, the main thing,
you know, people with autism are still
people whether people prefer "people
with autism", because you put the
people first or "autistic people".
Whatever your preference
of wording is you're still
people, so you should really...
the confidentiality should be respected as
you would expect any other person, really.
Kerry: I think it's important to maintain
confidentiality with anybody that you work
with, you know, cause I was a mainstream
teacher and now I work in a special
needs school, it's important to have
that confidentiality with every people.
Zoe: It's very important to
maintain confidentiality when
working with children with autism.
It's important that not
sharing information that they
may not want to be shared.
And so when sharing information, it's
important to get the consent from the
child or young person to actually share.
Ellen: Because you need
that level of trust.
And if I broke that trust, I mean, it's
taken me about a year, cause I've only
been here about a year, to build those
relationships with the young people.
So if they kind of found out that I
had said something about them, about
their personal lives or whatever,
they probably wouldn't trust me.
Zoe T: Whatever they want to remain
confidential, I think, other than
if it was a safeguarding issue, if
the, you know, whatever it is that
needed to be confidential from their
perspective, but if it was going to be
a safeguarding issue, then obviously
you couldn't keep that confidential.
Ellen: We can obviously go to our
safeguarding leads if we're worried
about that young person to kind
of get them the best help, but you
wouldn't see us kind of going outside
of here and being like, oh, you know,
"child A has done blah, blah, blah".
Phil: The chances are there's going
to be as well as a diagnosis of
autism, chances are, there's going
to be lots of other additional needs
around that as we often find with our
pupils - might be mental health issues,
of a Fitbit or physical health issues.
Might be family trauma
and things like that.
Zoe T: Well, I think that has to be led
by the person with autism themselves
or the family, if the person with
autism can't advocate for themselves.